该钱德 好
-Okay,Chandler. -Okay.
你的星座运势说：本月5日 某个特别的人会送你礼物
And your horoscope says:"On the 5th,a special someone will give you a gift."
那就先谢了
Well,thank you in advance.
却会在12日引发口角
"But the 12th brings a lover's spat."
你要取笑我送你的礼物 为什么？
You're going to make fun of my present.Why would you do that?
19日有人会向你表白
Wait. "On the 19th,a secret crush announces itself."
大家好
-Hey,guys. -Hey.
天哪，是“麦克与吉事”的 乔伊崔比亚尼
It's Joey Tribbiani of Mac and C.H.E.E.S.E.
是的，你今天开拍
That's right. It's your first day.
准备好跟你的机器人拍档打击邪恶势力了吗？
Are you psyched to fight crime with your robot sidekick?
还用问吗？在电视剧里担当主角？ 我想了好多年了
Am I? The lead in my own TV series?I've dreamed about this for years!
怎么可能没有准备好？
Why have I not been preparing?
你一定会演得很棒
You're gonna be great.
但我得跟机器人对戏 我对科技一窍不通
But I gotta act with a robot. I know nothing about technology.
我只会用钱德的电脑 找色情网站
I can't even use Chandler's computer,except to find porn.
那还是因为那是首页
And that's only because it's there when you turn it on.
我们本月份的口角会提前发生 我等你
Our spat will start early this month.I'll be waiting.
本集播出：“罗斯见伊丽莎白的父亲”
The One Where Ross Meets Elizabeth's Dad
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯阿奎特
丽莎库卓
麦特勒布兰
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
你看封面选书？这样不对喔
Are you judging them by their covers? You're really not supposed to.
不是，我想选一本来用 我又要写书了
I'm deciding which one to use. I'm going to write another book.
因为上一本很畅销？
Because the last one was such a big seller?
告诉你，我已经写了十四本书
If you must know,I have written 14 books.
因为读者只有我一个
And as I'm the only one who has read them...
我可以告诉你们，反应很热烈
I can tell you that they have been well received.
但是火灾把那些书都烧了
But I lost all of them in the fire.
所以这本我要收在防火箱里 放得离瑞秋远远的
So this one I'm gonna keep in an asbestos-lined box far away from Rachel.
我原谅她
Who I forgive.
你们等一下有事吗？
What are you doing later?
瑞秋和我要去剪头发
Rachel and I have to get our hair cut.
有吗？ 我想先知道他要干嘛
-We do? -I wanna see what he wants.
我刚得知伊丽莎白她爸想见我
Elizabeth's dad wants to meet me.
等等，且慢
Wait a minute. Hold the phone.
你不是伊丽莎白的爸爸？
You're not Elizabeth's dad?
你只能损我这一次
That's the only one you get.
他讨厌我
And he hates me.
他问伊丽莎白为何要跟一个 不交同年龄女友的男人约会
He asked Elizabeth why she'd want to go out with a guy...who couldn't get a girl his own age.
那她怎么说？
And what did she say to that?
你也不能再损我了
And that's yours.
拜托啦，我真的想让他喜欢我 你们要是能帮我一下就太好了
Come on. I really want this guy to like me.It would really help if you guys could make me look good.
我们当然帮你了  谢谢
-Of course we'll help. -Thanks.
谁都知道参加家长会很辛苦
We know how tough those parent-teacher conferences can be.
这是你的办公室场景
-So here's your office set. -Wow!
麦克麦可维利，私家侦探
Mac Machiavelli,private investigator.
你看我读这么多书
Look at all the books I've read.
我带你去试戏服 好
Let's get you to wardrobe.
什么时候跟机器人见面？
When do I meet the robot?
抱歉，那就现在吧，他也在
Right now. He's right here.
乔伊崔比亚尼，这位…
Joey Tribbiani,this is..
真是栩栩如生
Wow! He's so lifelike.
了不起 这位是创造、操作吉事的韦恩
Unbelievable.This is Wayne,the man who created and operates C.H.E.E.S.E.
韦恩，你好
How do you do there,buddy?
你们两个慢慢聊 好
I'll let you two guys get acquainted.
刚才很抱歉
Sorry about that.
吉事呢？ 吉事就在这里
-So where's C.H.E.E.S.E.? -C.H.E.E.S.E. is right here.
麦克，幸会
Nice to meet you,Mac.
它是半成品吧？
-This is the temporary robot,right?
不是，怎么了？
-No. Why?
我以为它会长得很酷
I thought it was gonna be a really cool robot.
像终结者，或刚才的你
Like the Terminator,or when I first saw you.
我花了2年研发这台机器 它非常先进
I spent two years developing this. It's state of the art.
抱歉，只是它看起来一无是处
Sorry. It doesn't look like it can do anything.
它会这样
It can do this.
布鲁斯・威利斯
Bruce Willis
这是我爸，保罗史提芬斯 爸，这是罗斯盖勒
This is my father,Paul Stevens. Dad,this is Ross Geller.
保罗，你好
It's great to meet you,Paul.
我比较喜欢伊丽莎白的男友 叫我史提芬斯先生
I prefer that Liz's boyfriends address me as Mr. Stevens.
没问题，史提芬斯先生
Of course. Mr. Stevens.
罗斯…
So,Ross...
你有什么毛病？
what's your problem?
什么？ 为什么不交年龄相近的女友？
Excuse me?Why can't you get a girlfriend your own age?
真好笑…
It's funny...
不好笑
It's not funny.
我不喜欢你跟我女儿交往
I don't like you going out with my daughter,Ross.
好，我看得出来
Okay,I can see that.
但要是你给我机会 我一定能改变你的看法
I think if you give me one chance,I can change your mind.
好
-Okay.
什么？ 好，我给你机会改变我的看法
-What?Okay. I'll give you one chance to change my mind.
计时1分钟
You've got one minute.
爸 好吧
-Daddy.
2分钟，开始
-Fine. Two minutes. Go.
1分50秒
A minute and 50 seconds.
好，我以前没做过这种事
I want you to know,I've never done anything like this before.
我是说我跟别人交往过
I mean,I've been in relationships in general.
但是我没跟学生做过…不…
But I've never done it with a student. I mean,not...
不是那档事，我们还没做过
Not "it." We haven't done "it."
当然我们做过一些事…
I mean,we've done stuff...
好，讲个笑话轻松一下
Okay. A joke. Lighten the mood.
两个男人走进酒吧 一个是爱尔兰人
Two guys go into a bar. One of them is Irish.
我是爱尔兰人 结果爱尔兰人赢了
-I'm Irish. -And the Irish guy wins the joke.
罗斯，居然会在这里遇见你
Ross! How crazy that we would run into you.
天哪，谢谢你们
Oh,my God! Thank you.
史提芬斯先生，他们是我朋友 菲比，莫妮卡和钱德
I'd like you to meet my friends. This is Phoebe,Monica and Chandler.
菲比，莫妮卡
-Phoebe. -Hello.-Monica. -Hi.
强德
Chunder.
是钱德 我记不住的
-Chandler. -Never going to remember that.
你是伊丽莎白的父亲？ 难怪她有一种…
You're Elizabeth's dad? I see where she gets her...
粗犷的美
rugged handsomeness.
你有史提芬斯夫人吗？
Is there a Mrs. Stevens?
你有宾先生
There's a Mr. Bing!
没有，丽莎出生不久 她妈妈就过世了
Unfortunately,Lizzie's mom passed away after she was born.
我一手把她带大
I raised her by myself.
我常碰上这种反应
I get that a lot.
好，大家都坐吧
Why don't we all take a seat?
我去帮大家点个咖啡
I'll get us all some coffees.
你来
Yeah,why don't you...
你们先随便聊 想到什么就聊什么
Talk about whatever you want.Whatever pops into your head.
我
me
这时候在这里遇见罗斯真怪 他通常都要去儿童医院
It is strange seeing Ross here,this time of day...because usually he's at the children's hospital.
不是去约会喔
But not looking for dates.
莫妮卡是罗斯的妹妹
Monica is Ross's sister.
他是个很棒的哥哥 我也有一个妹妹
He's a great brother!I had a sister.
她过世了
She passed away.
你们不必每次都这样
You don't have to do that every time.
不过罗斯人真的很好 我们是大学室友，好笑的是…
But Ross is a great guy. I was roommates with him in college.Funny story...
你的大学室友死了对吧？
Your roommate in college died,didn't he?
他算是半死不活
A part of him did,yes.
来吧，保罗，伊丽莎白 希望你们有找到话题
Here we are,Paul,Elizabeth.I hope you guys are finding something to talk about.
我们正在… 抱歉我来晚了
-Yes. We were just.. -Sorry I'm late.
不过我已经准备好要捧你了
But I am ready to talk you up.
丽莎的爸爸什么时候来？ 我已经来了
-When does Liz's father get here? -I'm already here.
罗斯人最好了
Ross is so great!
菲比，书写得怎样？
Hey,Phoebe. How's the book writing going?
很好，我写到47页了
Really well. I'm up to page 47.
你在写些什么？ 页数
-Wow! What are you writing? -Page numbers.
你买印小女生的 你明明说要买印小宝宝的
Honey,you got the kind with the little girl.You said you'd buy the kind with the baby.
你说那个小宝宝有点恐怖 是小女生有点恐怖
-You said the baby creeps you out. -The little girl does.
你是说小宝宝
-You said the baby.
小宝宝为什么会恐怖？ 小女生为什么会恐怖？
-Why would a baby creep me out?Why would the little girl creep you out?
抱歉，你们讲慢一点好吗？ 你要写进书里？
Can you please talk a little slower?-This is for your book?
对，这是探讨男女关系的书 尔虞我诈，各种禁忌
-It's about relationships.The traps,the pitfalls,what not to do.
继续，太精彩了
Keep going. This stuff's great.
你说什么？
Excuse me.
还有真心相爱就能克服一切
And how none of it matters when the people really love each other.
还有人都喜欢听好话
And how people will believe anything as long as it's a compliment.
我把钥匙掉在这里
-I left my keys here somewhere.
那赶快找
-Well,let's look for them.
是这一串吗？
Hey,look! Are these them?
不是
No.
好吧
All right.
在这里
-Here they are.
太好了 谢谢你
-Good.-Thanks for your help. -Wait! Sorry!
保罗先生
-Mr. Paul?
叫我保罗就好 保罗
-Just call me Paul.Paul.
我只是想说，罗斯人真的很好
I just wanted you to know that...Ross really is a great guy.
不如你跟他交往 省得我宰了他
Maybe you could date him. It'd save me the trouble of killing him.
怎么了？ 你不像是有20岁女儿的人
Are you okay?You don't look old enough to have a 20-year-old daughter.
我们生她的时候很年轻 我们？
Well,we were very young when we had her.-We?
对，一男一女才能…
-It usually takes two people to...
当然，我知道
Oh,no! Yes! Of course. I know that!
现在也是我们 还是只剩下你？
What I meant was are you still "we" or are you just you?
只有我，丽莎出生没多久 我老婆就死了
I'm just me.My wife died shortly after Lizzie was born.
你一手把她带大？ 对
So you raised her all on your own?Yes,I did.
你在写什么？ 我在画你
-What are you writing there? -I'm drawing a picture of you.
真好 但要是有穿衣服有头会更好
Well,that's very flattering.But it'd be great if you could draw me with some clothes and a head.
第一天顺利吗？
How was your first day?
不错，但机器人的态度有点差
Pretty good. Except I got attitude from the robot.
那些死机器人 它们应该是人类忠实的仆人
Damn those robots. They're supposed to be our faithful servants!
不是机器人，是操作它的人 他不喜欢我
It was the guy who controls the robot.He hates me.
我正要拿三明治 他就让吉事打翻盘子
He had C.H.E.E.S.E. knock over the sandwich table...right when I was reaching for one.
你怎么不解雇他？
Why don't you get him fired?
搞不好我会 我也不想，但我是主角
I may have to. I hate to do it. But I'm the star,you know?
总不能老捡地上的三明治吃
There's a limit to how many sandwiches I can eat off the floor.
抱歉
Excuse me.
乔伊崔比亚尼
Joey Tribbiani.
乔伊，找到你就好，有试镜
Joe! I'm glad I found you! I got an audition for you.
这件事是个秘密
But it's kind of on the q.t.
那个演员不知道 他可能会被换掉
The actor who has the part doesn't know he might be fired.
是一部电视剧的主角 “麦克与吉事”
It's the lead in a series.Mac and C.H.E.E.S.E.
我就是“麦克与吉事”的主角
I'm the lead in Mac and C.H.E.E.S.E.
乔伊？
Joey?
罗斯
Hi,Ross.
我在让他喜欢你
I was just getting him to like you.
乔伊？乔伊？
Joey!
罗斯，乔伊不在
Ross,Joey is not here.
好，那我在房里面等
I'll just wait for him in here!
罗斯，没关系，你可以出来
Ross,it's okay. You can come out.
没错，没关系，是我 史提芬斯先生
Yeah. It's okay. It's me...Mr. Stevens.
天哪，我刚才没看见你
I didn't... Oh,my gosh. I didn't even see you.
当然有，你走进来，觉得很尴尬
You did. You came in,got all awkward
就跑进房里去 还大叫“乔伊，乔伊”
and ran to the bedroom.You were shouting,"Joey!"
再见瑞秋  再见
-Bye,Rachel. -Bye.
我再打给你
I'll call you later.
好，再见 罗斯再见
-See you. -Bye,Ross.
你在…你怎么…你在怎么？
What? What the..? How did...? What?
他的钥匙掉了，就回来找
You know,he lost his keys. So he was looking for them.
在你的嘴里找？
In your mouth?
不是，在楼下找 我们聊了2小时，我很喜欢他
No!Downstairs. And we got to talking...for two hours. I liked him.
就请他上来喝杯咖啡
I invited him for coffee.
你们本身就在咖啡馆里
You were at the coffeehouse!
就算我亲了他又怎样？
What's the big deal? So I kissed the guy.
他是我的女朋友的爸爸 这样很怪
He is my girlfriend's father. It's weird!
你还不是跟我妹约会 那不一样
-You dated my sister! -That was different!
为什么？ 这次是我觉得怪
-What? Why? -This is weird for me!
罗斯，这样对你有好处
Ross,look. This is good for you.
承认吧 目前他一点也不喜欢你
Let's face it. So far the guy's not loving you.
但我可以扭转形势，我有门路
But I can turn that around. I've got the inside track.
我们可以一起去吃饭 我可以把你捧上天
We could all go out to dinner. And I could talk you up.
况且他是个超有名的律师
Plus the guy is a very successful lawyer.
这个为什么重要？ 可重要了
-How is that important? -It's important!
结果有一大帮人可以演麦克
There's a million guys who can play Mac...
机器人和操作员却都只有一个
and there's one robot.And this one guy who controls it.
我不知道他能让我失业 我该怎么办？
I didn't know he could get me fired.What am I gonna do?
乔伊，你很有魅力
-You're a pretty charming guy.
谢了，但我有问题要解决
Thanks. But I have a problem to deal with.
你得让那个操作员喜欢你
No,you've got to win over the guy who controls C.H.E.E.S.E.
你得用力拍他的机器马屁
Go back there and kiss some serious robot ass!
这个主意不错
That's not a bad idea!
既然明天要施展魅力 现在还是别浪费在你们身上的好
If I have to be charming tomorrow,I'm not wasting it on you guys.
不过菲比，我为你留了一点
I got some saved for you,Phoebe.
你觉得乔伊比我有魅力？
Do you think Joey is more charming than me?
对，所以我跟他有一腿
Yeah. That's why I'm sleeping with him on the side.
你想得美喔
You wish.
“你想得美喔”
"You wish."
菲比，别再写我们了 我没有，我是在写别人
Stop writing about us.I'm not writing about you. I'm writing about other people.
谁？ 莫莎和钱特
-Who? -Marsha and Chester.
好，那我就来写菲莉丝
Fine. Then you know what? I will just write about Phyllis.
菲莉丝坐在椅子上
-"Phyllis is sitting in the chair."
我知道你想干嘛
-I see what you're doing.
菲莉丝知道我想干嘛
"Phyllis sees what I'm doing."
哇，我终于自食恶果了
I have tasted my own medicine and it is bitter!
早，我最欣赏的天才 和我的机器人兄弟好吗？
Morning!How's my favorite genius and his robot?
别碰他 好
-Don't touch him! -Okay.
韦恩，老实说
Level with me.
我一直听说我会被换掉
I keep hearing rumors that I might get fired.
他们还找人来试我这个角色
They even have actors reading for my part.
拜托啦，再给我一次机会
Come on. You gotta give me a second chance.
我爱死这个小家伙了…
I love this little guy.
难怪你不让我碰他，对吧
That's why you didn't want me to touch him,right?
难以置信，上帝啊
I can't believe it. God!
你好吗？
Hey,how are you doing?
看样子我是被放鸽子了 罗斯就大方的提议要带我去
So it seemed that my prom date had stood me up.So Ross selflessly offered to take me.
好感人喔
What a nice story.
罗斯上大学时想趁虚而入 带一名少女参加高中舞会
So Ross was in college...and decided to jump at the chance to take a young girl to her prom.
想不到会有这种反效果
I definitely did not see that one backfiring.
我去洗手间 你慢慢上
-I'm going to the bathroom. -Take your time.
其实我是大一，她是高三 所以没那么…
I was a freshman and she was a senior. So it wasn't as bad as..
罗斯，我知道我一直找你麻烦
Look. I know I've been giving you a lot of jabs.
因为我很保护丽莎
It's partly because I'm very protective of Lizzie...
而且你的缺点实在很多
and partly because they just keep coming to me.
但是丽莎一直夸你 瑞秋又说了那么多事
I admit after all the wonderful things Lizzie told me...and the many,many,many stories that Rachel has told me...
看来你也…没那么糟
well...you're not...all bad.
是没那么糟
"Not all bad."
很抱歉之前对你那么凶 你必须知道
I'm sorry I was so harsh. But you have to understand.
丽莎在我眼中仍是个12岁的小女孩
I still look at Lizzie like she's a 12-year-old girl.
我懂你的意思，我也有同感
I know what you mean. I do that too.
你说什么？
-I beg your pardon?
不…我不是把她当成12岁的小女孩
-I don't see her as a 12-year-old.
我是说我有个6岁的儿子 在我眼中仍是个小宝宝
I mean,I have a son who is 6 and I still think of him as a baby.
你有儿子？ 对，我和前妻取得共同监护权
-A son? -My ex-wife and I share custody of Ben.
还有，卡萝和我的关系很好 相信你和你太太也是
Incidentally,Carol and I are on excellent terms...as I'm sure you are with your wife.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真蠢
It's unbelievable!
没事，我只是不知道你结过婚
Don't worry. I didn't realize you were married.
我们是结过婚，那只是…
We were. But that was just a...
那只是酒后闹事
That was just a big drunken mistake.
你回来了
You're back.
你们结过婚？
You two were married?
抱歉，你在讲艾蜜莉
I'm sorry. You were talking about Emily.
钱德，我们是约6点楼下见
We said we would meet at the coffeehouse at 6:00.
我们是约7点 我们是约6点
We said 7:00.We said 6:00!
我如果有讲到6点 应该是说：我们约7点
The only way that I said 6:00...would be if I said the sentence,"Let's meet at 7:00,
不要约6点
not at 6:00."
我如果有讲到7点，应该是说
If I had said 7:00,I would have said:
“我男朋友真自作聪明” “什么7点”
"My boyfriend is such a wiseass. 7:00!"
天哪
-Hi! -Oh,my good God!
我知道你们约几点 什么？
-I know what time you said. -What?
我知道莫莎和钱特约几点
Well,I know what time Chester and Marsha said.
几点？
What time?
真有趣的转变 我的书突然成了救星
Interesting turn of events.Suddenly it's my book to the rescue. Let's see
有意思，这样就很清楚了
Very interesting.Well this certainly clears things up.
到底是几点？
What does it say?
你们谢谢我写书，我就说
I will tell you as soon as you thank me for writing my book.
谢谢你写书
Thank you for writing your book.
这真是一本好书 你是女王中的女王
It's a great book...and you are the queen of everything.
谢谢，你也是
Thanks. So are you.
我就说我不该穿这个颜色
I told you I should not wear this color.
莫…莫莎和钱特 打算星期天晚上去看电影
"Monica.. Marsha and Chester are planning on seeing a movie Sunday.
莫莎觉得应该约6点 钱特觉得电影是7点
"Marsha thinks they're meeting at 6:00. Chester thinks it's 7:00."
你知道我们会赶不上电影？ 没错
-You knew we were gonna miss the movie? -Right.
而你只把它写在那本蠢书里 却不告诉我们？
Instead of telling us,you decided to write it in your stupid book?
莫莎和钱特很气菲莉丝
"Marsha and Chester are mad at Phyllis."
我居然要被换角
I can't believe I'm gonna lose this job.
真可惜，我能帮什么忙吗？
I'm so sorry,man. Is there anything I can do?
能，帮我把那个小冰箱搬走
Help me get this mini-fridge past the security guard.
乔伊，我有事找你
Joey,I want to talk to you.
我可不想理你
I don't want to talk to you.
我恨你，你毁了我的一生
I hate you. You ruined my life.
钱德，韦恩，韦恩，钱德
-Chandler,Wayne. Wayne,Chandler. -Hi.
乔伊，你帮我 我就叫他们不要换角
I'll get you your job back if you help me out.
我为什么要帮你？
Why should I help you out?
理由他已经说了
-The reason he just said.
帮你什么？
-What do you need?
我看到你跟那个美女说话 就是莎拉
I saw you on stage talking to that beautiful woman.You know,Sarah.
我很想跟她说话 你爱上她了吗？
I wish I could talk to her.-Are you in love with her?
对，她，所有的女人 谁都好
-Yeah.Her. All of them. Anyone.
我是过来人
Yeah. I've been there,my friend.
你教我跟女人搭讪 我保证让你留下来
Listen,I guarantee you keep your job...if you can teach me to talk to women like you do.
韦恩，这种事是教不来的 这是一种天生的…
You can't teach it. It's something you're born with.
教得来，我教你
You can teach it. I can show you right now.
真的？ 当然，我就教过他
-Really? -Sure. Yeah. I taught him.
我找到了我完全配不上的女人
Yeah. You should see the woman I'm with,way out of my league.
我可以把他女友转给你
In fact,if you want,I can get you her.
其实罗斯每次结婚 都学到一点东西
Well,if you think about it...Ross did learn something from each marriage.
学到如何让婚姻变短吗？
How to make the next one even shorter?
等等，这么说不公平
Wait a minute. That's not fair.
我们的婚姻比他和艾蜜莉的长 他只是没告诉我
He was married to me a hell of a lot longer than he was to Emily.He just didn't tell me.
我再撒一次尿好了
Maybe I have to pee again.
真有意思
Well,this is fun.
罗斯，有哪个老婆被你杀了吗
So,Ross,did you kill any of these wives?
你知道吗？我受够了
I have had enough of this!
我很喜欢你的女儿 我一直很尊重她
I care a great deal about your daughter.And I have treated her with respect!
要是你对我有意见，说实话…
So if you've got a problem with me..
你在朝我吼叫吗？ 绝对没有
-Are you yelling at me? -God,no.
爸，你不喜欢罗斯也无所谓
You know what? If you don't like Ross,that's fine.
我不管，我还是要跟他交往
It doesn't matter. I'm going out with him anyway.
真的？
Really?
要是她不管，那我也不管
Well,if it doesn't matter to her...it doesn't matter to me.
这不是吼叫喔
Still not yelling.
我还能说什么呢
What can I say?
我并没有比较喜欢你 没关系，我也不太喜欢我自己
I still don't like you.I'm not so crazy about myself right now either.
所以我们达成共识 对，可以这么说
-Then we agree? -I guess so.
我们没有人喜欢罗斯 我喜欢罗斯
-Neither of us like Ross. -I like Ross.
小孩子
Kids!
等等 我又想到罗斯人很好的实例了
I just thought of a story about how nice Ross is.
没关系，我们现在不喜欢罗斯
That's okay. We're not liking Ross right now.
这种实例也很多
Well,I got a lot of those too.
结果你是对的，吉事
You were right,C.H.E.E.S.E.
那批货根本没抵达阿马哈？
-The shipment never made it to Omaha?
没错，而且那个法师的胡子 100%是马鬃
-You got it.And the rabbi's beard? 100 percent horsehair.
干得好，吉事
Nice catch,C.H.E.E.S.E.
吉事，该你了
It's your line,C.H.E.E.S.E.
韦恩！韦恩
Wayne! Wayne!